Guide to the Phi Mu, Gamma Epsilon Chapter (Duke University) Records, 1934-1982
Duke University. University Archives
Phi Mu, Gamma Epsilon Chapter (Duke University) records 1934-1982
Duke University. University Archives
Phi Mu. Gamma Epsilon Chapter (Duke University).
17.0 linear feet Extent: about 300 Items
The Gamma Epsilon chapter was established at Duke University in 1934 as a social fraternity for women college students. Type of material includes scrapbooks, photographs, minutes, a constitution, and songbook. Major topics include student life at Duke University, sororities, initiation, and general management of a fraternal organization. The material ranges in date from 1934-1982.
UA.31.22.0008
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Some of the material is in off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Phi Mu, Gamma Epsilon Chapter (Duke University) Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973, 1981.
Historical Note
The Gamma Epsilon Chapter of Phi Mu, was established at Duke University in 1934. New members took part in their first Greek events in November 1934. These events included the Phi Psi installation, a Carolina pep meeting, a Sigma Nu dance, and a co-ed ball. Rachel Meetze served as the Gamma Epsilon chapter's first president. The chapter dissolved in 1987 and is no longer active at Duke University.
Collection Overview
The collection includes scrapbooks, photographs, minutes, printed material, a constitution, and songbook. Major topics include student life at Duke University, sororities, initiation, and general management of a fraternal organization. The material ranges in date from 1934-1982.
Subject Headings
Phi Mu. Gamma Epsilon Chapter (Duke University); Duke University -- Societies, etc.; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.)
Related Material
Panhellenic Council Records
Duke University Archives
Fraternities and Sororities Collection
Duke University Archives
Woman's College Records
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Scrapbooks, 1934-1980, (11) Boxes
  Contains scrapbooks and yearbooks of the Gamma Epsilon chapter. These books include materials about "Little Sister/Big Sister" events, pledging, rush, dances, parties, and press received by the fraternity. The 1934 scrapbook contains the petition for a charter.
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1936-1940 (Box 2)
  - 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - 1936 (Box 3)
  - 1940-1942 (Box 4)
  - 1947-1949 (Box 4)
  - 1949-1958 (Box 4)
  - circa 1940s (Box 5)
  - 1947 (Box 5)
  - 1952-1953 (Box 14)
  - 1955-1957 (Box 6)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - 1961-1966 (Box 7)
  - 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Album of photographs and composites, circa 1930s-1980 (Box 11)
- Chapter Minutes, 1934-1972, (1) Box (Box 11)
  Contains the minutes of house meetings. Topics include general business, social, and civic activities of the chapter.
  - 1934-1937 (Box 12)
  - 1938-1945 April (Box 12)
  - 1945 Sept.-1953 (Box 12)
  - 1953-1960 (Box 12)
  - 1960-1972 (Box 12)
  - 1975-1976 (Box 12)
- Printed Materials, 1958-1982, (2) Boxes (Box 12)
  Contains The Aglaia, the newsletter of the Phi Mu headquarters, and Songs of Phi Mu, also published by the headquarters. The 1980 and 1982 issues contain references to the Gamma Epsilon chapter.
  - The Aglaia, 1958-1959/1968-1969 (Box 12)
  - The Aglaia, 1969-1970/1976, 1980, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Songs of Phi Mu, 1960 (Box 13)
- Other Materials, circa 1950-1980, (1) Box (Box 13)
  Contains constitution and bylaws of the national headquarters, materials used during pledging, and photographs. Also see Series 1 for composite photographs.
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Convention program, 1952 (Box 13)
  - Pledge materials, circa 1972 (Box 13)
  - Photographs, circa 1950-1952 (Box 13)
  - Photographs, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Photographs, 1979, 1980 (Box 13)